Guide to the Luis Leal Papers, 1946-1985
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3: Manuscripts of articles, lectures, presentations
  - Subseries F: Luis Leal published articles, lectures, etc. (numbers refer to listings in Luis Leal, A Bibliography with Interpretative and Critical Essays. Eds. Salvador Güereña and Raquel Quiroz González. Berkeley: Chicano Studies Library Publications Unit, University of California at Berkeley, 
    - III. Contributions to books: #100 - "El Siglo de oro de Balbuena: primera novela americana." In Homenaje a Andrés Iduarte. Ed. Jaime Alazraki, et al. Clear Creek, Indiana: The American Hispanist, 1976, pp. 217-228. Rpt. KRQ, 23, No. 3 (1976), pp. 327-334. #101 - "Sor Juana Inés de la Cruz." Enciclopedia Britannica. 1960 ed. #103 - "Tradición y cosmopolitismo en la maestra normal." Commemorative Series: Eight Essays on Manuel Gálvez Baluzera. Riverside: University of California: Latin American Studies Program, 1982, pp. 65-79. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - IV. Introductions to books: #105 - Anuario del cuento mexicano. México: INBA, 1961. #106 - The Art of Mariano Azuela: Modernismo in La malhora, El desquite, La Luciernaga. By Eliud Martínez. Pittsburg, Pa: Latin American Literary Review Press, 1980. #107 - Las cinco palabras. By Ramón Rubín. México: Fondo de Cultura Económica, 1969. #113 - La novelística de Carlos Droguett. By Francisco A. Lomelí. Madrid: Nova Scholar, 1983. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - V. Articles and essays: #116 - "Agustín Yáñez y la novela mexicana. Rescate de una teoría." Revista Iberoamericana, 48, No. 118-119, (1982), 121-129. Rpt. Mester, 12, (1983, 18-25. #117 - "La alborada del cuento social en México." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No.865, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 27 Oct. 1963, p. 1. #119 - "The American In Mexican Literature." Melus, 5, No.3 (1978), 16-25. #120 - "Andrés Iduarte, el hombre y su vida." Vida Latina, 3, No. 6 (1954), 6, 16. #121 - "Aportaciones de Hispanoamérica a la cultura de los Estados Unidos." Hispania, 35 (1951), 245-250. #122 - "La aracauna y el problema de la literatura nacional." Vórtice, 1, No. 1 (1974), 68-73. #123 - "Arquetipos femeninos en la cultura mexicana." Proceedings of the Pacific Coast Council of Latin American Studies (1980-81), pp. 79-82. #124 - "Aspects of the Mexican Novel: From Lizardi to Elizondo." Arizona Quarterly, 24, No. 1 (1968), 53-64. #125 - "Borges y la novela." Revista Iberoamericana, 36, (1970), 11-23. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - V. Articles and essays: #128 - "Cinco de Mayo Impressions." Encuentro, 8, No. 4 (1984), 6-7. #129 - "El Códice Ramírez y el P. Tovar." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 759, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 15 Oct. 1961, p. 3. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - V. Articles and essays: #130 - "La Colección de poesias mexicanas atribuida a José María Luis Mora." Boletín Bibliográfico de la Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público, 16, No. 440 (1970), 4-7. #133 - "El contenido literario de 'La Orquesta'." Historia Mexicana, 7 (1958), 329-367. #136 - "Crítica cinematográfica, por Xavier Villaurrutia; selección de Luis Leal." Estaciones, 4, No. 13 (1959), 15-27. #139 - "La Cucaracha." Revista Universidad de México, 8, No. 5 (1954), 15-17. Rpt. Nuestra Década, v. 2, México: UNAM, 1964. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - V. Articles and essays: #140 - "Cuentistas mexicanos: Cipriano Campos Alatorre." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 823, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 6 Jan. 1963, pp. 1, 4. #141 - "Cuentistas mexicanos: Francisco Rojas González." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 811, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 14 Oct. 1962, pp. 8-9. #142 - "Cuentistas mexicanos: Manuel Alvarez del Castillo." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 1000, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 29 May 1966, p. 2. #143 - "Cuentistas mexicanos: Ramón Rubín." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 892, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 3 May 1964, p. 1. #145 - "Un cuento de Fray Manuel de Navarrete." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 18 Mar. 1962, p. 5. #146 - "Un cuento de Juan José Arreola." El Rehilete, 2a Epoca, No. 29 (1969), pp. 46-48. #147 - "El cuento de la Revolución mexicana." El Libro y el Pueblo, Epoca IV, No. 7 (163), 14-25. #148 - "El cuento mexicano de protesta social." Boletín Agrupación por la Formación Integral del Adolescente, Nos. 5-6, (1964), pp.27-37. Rpt. Islas, [inc.] (1965), 105-112. Rpt. Si Se Puede, 3, No. 3, [n.d.] 15-17. #149 - "Los cuentos de Borges." La Palabra y el Hombre, 27 (1963), 425-436. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - V. Articles and essays: #150 - "Los cuentos de Manuel José Othón." Armas y Letras, 2a Epoca, (1958), 1-19. #151 - "Los cuentos de Rojas González." La Gaceta, 6, No. 76 (1960), 4. #152 - " De lo escrito y que no muere." Cuadernos Americanos, No. 1 (1982), pp. 141-144. #153 - "Disertaciones y tesis sobre literatura mexicana en los Estados Un idos." Hispania,a 45, (1962), 281-383. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - V. Articles and essays: #155 - "Dos cuentos olvidados de Vicente Riva Palacio." Anales del Instituto de Investigaciones Estéticas, 27 (1958), 63-70. #156 - "El 'ejemplo', género literario popular." Revista Universidad de México, 8, No. 9, (1954), 14-17. #158 - "La enseñanza de la literatura hispanoamericana." Hispania, 56, (1973), 626-627. #165 - "Federico Gamboa y la novela mexicana." Ovaciones No. 177, 30 May 1965, p. 2. #166 - "La feria de Juan José Arreola: tema y estructura." Nueva Narrativa Hispanoamericana, 1, (1971), 41-48. Rpt. Revista de la Universidad de Guadalajara, 1 Jan. 1974, 1-6, unnumbered. Rpt. Perspectivas de nueva narrativa hispanoamericana: autores, (Rio Piedras, P.R., 1973) pp. 245-258. #168 - "Gabino Barreda y la literatura: De la Preparatoria al Ateneo." Aztlán, 14, No. 2 (1983), 153-163. #169 - "El gallo de oro de Juan Rulfo: guión o novela?." Foro Literario, Ano IV, 4, Nos, 7-8 (1980), 32-37. (Rpt. in La Comunidad See No. 265). (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - V. Articles and essays: #170 - "El gallo de oro y otros textos de Juan Rulfo." INTI Revista de Literatura Hispánica, Nos. 13-14 (1981), pp. 103-110.\ #173 - "Geografía cultural de México." Vida Latina, 4, No. 2 (1955), 3; No.3, pp. 5, 25; No. 4, p. 4. #174 - "El héroe acosado." Revista Universidad de México, 33, No. 8 (1979), 25-28. #175 - Hispanoamérica, su literatura y los Estados Unidos." La Gaceta, 11, No. 113 (1964), 5, 7. Rpt. Hispania, 47 (1964), 404-107. #178 - "La imagen literaria chicana." Xalmán, 2, No. 1 (1978), 5. #179 - "La imagen literaria chicana: Fruto del contraste entre dos culturas ." (Abstract). Adjoining Cultures as Reflected in Literature and Language. Proceedings on the XVth Triennial Congress of the Federation International des Langues et Litteratures Modernes. Arizona State University, Tempe, 1983, pp. 145-6. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - V. Articles and essays: #180 - "Imagen de la nueva novela hispanoamericana." Exilio, 6, No. 2 (1972), 47-57. #182 - "Jicotencal, primera novela historica en castellano." Revista Iberoamericana, 25 (1960), 9-31. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - V. Articles and essays: #183 - "The legend of Agustín Lorenzo." Western folklore, 29 (1965), 177-183. #184 - "La leyenda guadalupana." ABC, 12 Dec. 1942, pp. 3, 6. #185 - "El libro XII de Sahagún." Historia mexicana, 5 (1955), 184-210. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - V. Articles and essays: #186 - "La Licantropía entre los antiguos mexicanos." América Indígena, 20 (1960), 111-119. #186a - "Literary Criticism and Minority Literatures: The Case of the Chicano Writer." Confluencia, 1 No. 2 (1986), 4-9. #188 - "Los de abajo cincuenta años después." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 975, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 5 Dec. 1965, p. 1. #190 - "Luis González Obregón y la tradición nacional." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 969, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 24 Oct. 1965, p. 1. #191 - "Manuel Alvarez del Castillo." Et Caétera, 2a Epoca, 4, No. 15 (1969), 81-93. #192 - "Manuel Blanco, novelista olvidado." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 23 Feb. 1964, pp. 1, 2. #193 - "Mariano Azuela, novelista médico." Revista Hispánica Moderna, 28, No. 2-4 (1962), 295-303. #196 - "The Mexican Short Story." Arizona Quarterly, 12, No. 1 (1956), 24-34. 197 - "El México de Angel de Campo, Micros." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 955, Sunday Suppement to El Nacional, 18 July 1965, p. 1. #199 - "Mujer que sabe latín." Letras de Buenos Aires, 2 No. 7 (1982), 33-34. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - V. Articles and essays: #200 - "Myth and Social Realism in Miguel Angel Asturias.: Comparative Literature Studies, 5, (1968), 237-147. #203 - "Nicaragua en su literatura." Presente, 2a Etapa, No. 26 (1979), 15-25. #204 - "El norteamericano en la literatura mexicana." The Bilingual Review, 6, No. 1 (1979), 31-38. #205 - "Las novelas de Heriberto Frías." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 989, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 13 March 1966, p. 1. #206 - "Las 'Novelas rusticas' de Manuel José Othón." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 1026, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 27 Nov. 1966, p. 1. #207 - "La nueva narrativa mexicana." Nueva Narrativa Hispanoamericana, 20, No. 1 (1972), 89-97. #207a - "La nueva narrativa urbana." Tinta, 1 No. 5 (1987), 31-33. #208 - Nuevas expresiones, exhibición de arte chicano." Xalmán, 5, Nos. 1-2 (1983-1984), 69-73. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - V. Articles and essays: #209 - "Nuevos novelistas mexicanos." El Urugallo, 4, Nos. 35-36 (1975), 89-94. #210 - "Octavio Paz and the Chicano." Latin American Literary Review, 5, No. 10 (1977), 115-123. #211 - "Octavio Paz y la literatura nacional: afinidades y oposiciones." Revista Iberoamericana, 37, No. 74 (1971), 239-250. #212 - "Octavio Paz y la novela mexicana." Inter-American Review of Bibliography, 29, (1979), 305-313. #213 - "Para la bibliografía de Jalisco." Boletín Bibliográfico de la Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público. 2a Epoca, 15, No. 413, (1969), 14-17; No. 414 (1969), 10-11; No. 415 (1969), 16-17; No. 416 (1969), 16-17; No. 417 (1969), 15-16; No. 418 (1969), 16. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - V. Articles and essays: #214 - "Pedro Henríquez Ureña, crítico de la literatura hispanoamericana." Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 27, (1977), 241-253. #215 - "Pedro Henríquez Ureña en México." Revista Iberoamericana, 11 (1956), 119-133. #218 - "La poesía de Amado Nervo: a cuarenta años de distancia." Hispania, 43 (1960), 43-47. #220 - "Porfirio Martínez Peñaloza." Boletín Bibliográfico de la Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público, 2a Epoca, 15, No. 420 (1969), 4, 5. #224 - "Las primeras prosas de J. Rubén Romero." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 887, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1964), p. 1. #225 - "La protesta social como tema en el cuento mexicano." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 871, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1963), pp. 1, 4. #226 - "The Pursued Hero: 'La noche de Ramón Yendía'." Symposium, 24, No. 3 (1975), 255-260. #227 - "Radiografía de la muerte." Xalmán, 3, No. 1 (1980), 47-53. #229 - "Ramón Manterola, literato olvidado." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 768, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1961), p. 5. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - V. Articles and essays: #214 - "Pedro Henríquez Ureña, crítico de la literatura hispanoamericana." Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 27, (1977), 241-253. #215 - "Pedro Henríquez Ureña en México." Revista Iberoamericana, 11 (1956), 119-133. #218 - "La poesía de Amado Nervo: a cuarenta años de distancia." Hispania, 43 (1960), 43-47. #220 - "Porfirio Martínez Peñaloza." Boletín Bibliográfico de la Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público, 2a Epoca, 15, No. 420 (1969), 4, 5. #224 - "Las primeras prosas de J. Rubén Romero." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 887, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1964), p. 1. #225 - "La protesta social como tema en el cuento mexicano." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 871, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1963), pp. 1, 4. #226 - "The Pursued Hero: 'La noche de Ramón Yendía'." Symposium, 24, No. 3 (1975), 255-260. #227 - "Radiografía de la muerte." Xalmán, 3, No. 1 (1980), 47-53. #229 - "Ramón Manterola, literato olvidado." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, No. 768, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, (1961), p. 5. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - V. Articles and essays: #232 - "Recuerdos de Ciudad Juárez en escritores de la Revolución." Hispania, 47 (1964), 231-241. #235 - "Ruben Darío, novelista." Et Caétera, 2a Epoca, 3, No. 11 (1968), 51-62. #235a - "Rulfo ante el mundo norteamericano." México Indígena, numero extraordinario (1986), 22-24. #236 - "Salado Alvarez y los modernistas." Revista Mexicana de Cultura, Sunday Supplement to El Nacional, 1 Oct. 1967, p. 1. #237 - "Situación de Amado Nervo." Revista Iberoamericana, 36, (1970), 485-494. #238 - "Situación de Julio Cortázar." Revista Iberoamericana, 39, (1973), 399-409. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - V. Articles and essays: #240 - "La sombra del caudillo, roman a cléf." Modern language journal, 26 (1952), 16-21. #241 - "Los sonetos de Manuel José Othón." La palabra y el hombre, 6 (1958), 183-198. #242 - "The spanish short story and its potential for the secondary and college classroom." Foreign Language Annals, 5, (1972), 442-446. Rpt. The Canadian Modern Language Review, 30, (1974), 152-156. #243 - "A Spanish-American Perspective of Anglo-American Literature." Revista Canadiense de Estudios Hispánicos, 5, No.1 (1980), 61-73. #246 - "T latelolco, Tlatelolco." Denver Quarterly, 14, (1979), 3-14. (Issued of: Mexican Letters Since 1968). (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - V. Articles and essays: #247 - "El tocotín mestizo de Sor Juana." Abside, 18 (1954), 51-64. #248 - "Torres Bodet y los Contemporáneos." Hispania, 40 (1957), 290-296. #249 - "Trends in the Development of the Spanish-American Novel." Emory University Quarterly, 13 (1957), 27-34. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - V. Articles and essays: #250 - "Los tres 'Nocturnos' de Ruben Darío." Proceedings-Pacific Northwest Conference on Foreign Languages, Eighth Meeting, March 17-18, 18 (1967), pp. 202-207. #251 - "Una leyenda desconocida de Florencio M. del Castillo." Boletín Bibliográfico de la Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público. 2a Epoca, 20, No. 499 (1974), 18-19. #252 - "Una poesía de Octavio Paz." Hispania, 48, (1965), 841-842. (See No. 96). #253 - "Unamuno americanista." Cuadernos Americanos, 16 (1957), 183-190. #255 - "Vicente Rivas Palacio, cuentista." Revista Iberoamericana, 22 (1957), 301-309. #256 - "Vicente T. Mendoza y el folklore en México." Vida Latina, 3, No. 10 (1954), pp. 6, 21; No. 11, pp. 5, 6; No. 12, pp. 5, 9, 21; 4, No. 1 (1955), pp. 9, 20. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - V. Articles and essays: #256a - "Vida y muerte: el jardín como metáfora en la hija de Rappaccini." Ideas '92, 1, No. 1 (1987), 71-76. #257 - "Los Voladores: From Ritual to Game." New Scholar, 8 (1982), 129-142. #258 - "Las vueltas del tiempo. Continuidad o cambio en los personajes de Agustín Yañez." La Semana de Bellas Artes, No. 116, 20 Feb. 1980, pp. 2-4. #259 - "Xavier Villaurrutia, crítico." Estaciones, 4, No. 13 (1959), 3-14. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - VI. Articles in la Comunidad. (Sunday supplement to La Opinion. #262 - "En busca de Mariano Azuela." No. 143, 17 Apr. 1983, p. 3. #262a - "Conversando con Marco Antonio Montes de Oca." (with Margarita Rodríguez del Valle). No. 354, 3 May 1987, pp. 6-7, 15. #263a - "El Coyote: The rebel, novela prechicana olvidada." 14 Oct. 1984, pp. 12-13. #264 - "Los dos mundos de J. L. Borges." No. 189, 4 Mar. 1984, pp. 6-7. #266 - "Los límites formales del cuento." No. 183, 22 Jan. 1984, p. 3. #269 - "La lucha contra el caos." No. 162, 28 Aug. 1983, p. 2. #275 - "El Tiempo nublado de Octavio Paz." No. 203, 10 Jun. 1984, p. 12. #276 - "Ulises Criollo." No. 165, 18 Sept. 1983, pp. 10-11. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - VII. Book reviews: #278 - After the Storm: Landmarks of Modern Mexican Novel, by Joseph Sommers. Arizona Quarterly, 25 (1969), pp. 168-169. Also Hispanic Review, 38 (1970), 338-141. #279 - Breve historia de la novela mexicana, by John Brushwood and José Rojas Garcidueñas. Revista Iberoamericana, 26 (1961), 192-195. #280 - Breve historia de la poesía mexicana, by Frank Dauster. Revista Iberoamericana, 23 (1958), 198-200. #281 - El canto del aljibe, by Hugo Rodríguez Alcalá. Inter-American Review of Bibliography, 28 (1977), 426-429. #282 - Centauro al sol, by Germán Pardo García. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 27 (1961), 153-154. #283 - Colección Homenajes, by Helmy F. Giacoman. Sin Nombre, (San Juan, P.R.), 6, No. 2 (1975), 89-91. #284 - Compadre Lobo, by Gustavo Sainz. Hispamérica, 8, Nos. 23-24 (1979), 171-172. #285 - El corregidor Diego Díaz del Castillo (hijo del Conquistador) ante la Inquisición de México (1568-1571), by Winston A. Reynolds. Latin American Literary Review, 7, No. 13 (1978), 91-92. #286 - A Cultural History of Spanish America; from Conquest to Independence, by Mariano Picón Salas, trad. by Irving A. Leonard. Western Humanities Review, 18, No. 1 (1964), 85-86. #287 - Currents in the Contemporary Argentine Novel, by David William Foster. Hispania, 59 (1976), 383. #288 - Diccionario de escritores mexicanos, by Aurora M. Ocampo de Gómez and Ernesto Prado Vázquez. Revista Iberoamericana, 36, No. 72 (1970), 520-523. #289 - Don Q, by José Lopez Portillo. Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 28, No. 4 (1978), 434-435. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - VII. Book reviews: #290 - Edades poéticas (1922-1956), by Jorge Carrera Andrade. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 26 (1960), 118-119. #291 - Ensayos de norte a sur, by Hugo Rodríguez Alcalá. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 28 (1962), 65. #292 - Ensayos japoneses, by Manuel Maples Arce. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 27 (1961), 165. #293 - Epistolario y archivo, by Mariano Azuela. Revista Iberoamericana, 36 (1970), 131-134. #294 - Fábula de la verdad, by Claudia Lars. Hispania, 44 (1961), 354. #295 - Francisco González León, by Allen W. Phillips. Hispania, 49 (1966), 543-544. #296 - El grongo:cuentos, by Julio Ricci. Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 29 (1979), 100-102. #297 - Guillermo Prieto, by Malcolm D. Mclean. Hispania, 44 (1961), 173. #298 - Historia de la literatura hispanoamericana, by Carlos Hamilton. Revista Iberoamericana, 27 (1961), 373-385. #299 - Homage to Irving A. Leonard, ed. Raquel Chang-Rodríguez and Donald A. Yates. Revista Iberoamericana, 44 (1978), 591-593. #300 - Indice de El Renacimiento, by Huberto Batis. Hispania, 48 (1965), 394. #301 - Indice de "La Cultura en México" (1962-1972), by Alfonso González. Explicación de Textos Literarios, 8, No. 2 (1979-80), 229. #302 - Julio Ramón Ribeyro y sus dobles, by Wolfgang A. Luchting. Revista de Estudios Hispánicos, 10, No. 2 (1976), 317-319. #303 - Laberinto de Fortuna: un retrato el la geografía, by Arturo Uslar Pietri. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 30 (1964), 140-141. #304 - El laberinto de la soledad, by Octavio Paz. Revista Iberoamericana, 25 (1960), 184-186. #305 - Lázaro Pavía, prosista modernista, by Ofelia Malagamba Uriarte. Anuario de Letras, (UNAM), 3 (1963), 346-347. #305a - The Legend of La Llorona, by Rudolfo Anaya. Lector, 4, No. 1 (1986). #306 - Literatura hispanoamericana: Antología e introducción histórica, by Enrique Anderson Imbert and Eugenio Florit. Revista Iberoamericana, 28 (1962), 225-227. #307 - Luis González Obregón (1865-1938), by Leonardo C. de Morelos. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 24 (1958), 68-69. Also Revista Iberoamericana, 23 (1951), 200-202. #308 - Manifestación de silencios, by Arturo Azuela. Hispamérica, 10, No. 30 (1981), pp. 149-150. #309 - Mexico in American and British Letters, by Drewey Wayne Gunn. Comparative Literature Studies, 13, No. 1 (1976), 87-88. #310 - The Modern Short Story in Perú, by Earl M. Aldrich, Jr. Symposium, 24, No. 2 (1970), 176-178. #311 - Narraciones tzeltales de Chiapas, by Carlo Antonio Castro. La Palabra y el Hombre, 39 (1966), 515-516. #312 - Nezahualcóyotl, by José María Vigil. Revista Iberoamericana, 23 (1958), 465-467. #313 - Un niño en la Revolución mexicana, by Andrés Iduarte. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 20 (1954), 76-79. #313a - Nueva historia de la novela hispanoamericana, by Fernando Alegría. Revista Iberoamericana, 53, No. 140 (1987), 700-703. #314 - Obras, by Xavier Villaurrutia. Inter-American Review of Bibliography, 28 (1968), 323-326. #315 - Ocho modelos de felicidad, by Julio Ricci. Hispamérica, 10, No. 30 (1981), 161-163. #317 - Panorama de la iteratura española contemporánea, by Gonzalo Torrente Ballester. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 25 (1959), 232-234. #318 - Panorámica del cuento mexicano, ed. Victor Manuel Barcelo. Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 28, No. 3 (1978), 320-321. #318a - La poesía constructiva de Jaime Torres Bodet; un estudio de "Cripta" y de sus contextos, by Beth Kurti Miller. Revista Interamericana de Bibliografía, 26, No. 3 (1976), 331-33. #319 - La poesía femenina argentina (1810-1950), by Helena Percas. Hispania, 42 (1959), 459-460. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - VII. Book reviews: #320 - Presencia del humo, by Rául Cárdenas. Hispania, 44 (1961), 354. (See 294). #321 - El puente, by José Martínez Sotomayor. Revista Iberoamericana, 23 (1958), 467-468. #323 - Las revistas literarias de Hispanoamérica, by Boyd G. Carter. Hispania, 44 (1961), 175-176. #324 - El romanticismo en la América Hispánica, by Emilio Carilla. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 26 (1960), 148-149. #325 - Selected Poems of Pablo Neruda, ed. and tr. by Ben Belitt. Modern Language Journal, 48 (1964), 532-533. #326 - Septiembre y los otros días, by Jesús Gardea. Hispamérica, 11, No. 31 (1982), 103-105. #327 -Símbolo y color en la obra de José Martí, by Ivan Schulman. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 28 (1962), 354. #329 - Teoría y técnica del cuento, by Enrique Anderson Imbert. Hispanic Review, 50 (1982), 224-225. #330 - Tiempo nublado, by Octavio Paz. World Literature Today, 58, No. 3 (1984), 396-397. #331 - Tijeras y listones, by Luis Córdova. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 24 (1958), 66. #332 - Una luz en la orilla, by María Lombardo de Caso. Revista Hispánica Moderna, 27 (1961), 161-162. #333 - The Visits of the Queen of Sheba, by Miguel Serrano. Hispania, 45 (1962), 137. (Box 33, Folder 1)